Beni Mahat

(720) 226-6565 | benimahat6565@gmail.com | Boulder, CO 80304 linkedin.com/in/beni-mahat-1218b5184 | github.com/benimahat1291| bit.ly/benimahatportfolio

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer passionate about creating an ideal user web experience. Recently received a Certificate in Web Development from Denver University. A deadline driven excellent interpersonal communicator and proactive collaborator valued on team-based projects for critical thinking and technical problem-solving skills. Recognized ability to establish measurable goals and relentlessly work to achieve them.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Node.js, Express, JavaScript, jQuery, ES6, React.js, React, React Hooks, Next.js, JSX, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Materialize, Handlebars, Sever-side Rendering, Search-engine-optimization, NPM, GIT, GitHub, MongoDB, Mongoose, MySQL, NoSQL, Sequelize, Firebase, Mongoose, Heroku, Terminal, Axios, JSON.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE | PROJECTS

Eventor | **Link**: bit.ly/eventor123 | **GitHub**: github.com/benimahat1291/Eventor An event planner where users can create and discover detailed conference-like events.

- **Role**: Implemented MongoDB Backend with full CRUD functionality. Integrated Auth.0 library for user authentication. Created React Components with mobile responsive design. Deployed using Heroku.
- **Utilized**: HTML, ISX, CSS, ISON, Express, React, Axios, MongoDB, Auth.0, and Server-side APIs

Amazon-Clone | Link: bit.ly/ecommerceAmazon | **GitHub:** github.com/benimahat1291/AmazonClone.git/ A fully functioning E-commerce web page designed to resemble amazon.

- Role: Created and styled all react components. Built a fully functioning Firebase cloud function back-end, implemented Firebase authentication and deployment. Used React-Stripe library to process real-time credit card payments.
- **Utilized**: HTML, JSX, CSS, JSON, Express, React, Flexbox, Firebase, Stripe

Bookshelf | Link: bit.ly/bookshelflibrary | **GitHub:** github.com/benimahat1291/BookShelf.git An online library where users can loan and borrow books from other users.

- **Role**: Designed realistic bookshelf with a dynamic carousel component. Utilized books API for images and information to render in our application. Implemented a SQL database and deployed to Heroku.
- **Utilized**: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, AJAX, SQL, and Server-side APIs

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Zaika Indian Express; Denver, CO

02/2016 - 04/2020

Assistant Manager

Established a culture of outstanding customer service and the highest standard for food quality. Evaluate inventory and log daily sales reports. Troubleshoot technical issues throughout the store and build customer loyalty though personable interactions.

- Designed a menu adopted by the franchise of five locations throughout Colorado.
- Maintained an above average 4.5 restaurant rating throughout popular restaurant rating platforms.
- Aided in growth of annual sales by 40% from 2016-2019.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Certificate - Denver University: Denver, CO | 2020

A 12-week intensive boot camp program focused on gaining technical programming and market-driven skills.

104 credits hours completed towards a Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering - Colorado University: Boulder, CO